lssproducts.com 2004-10-10

# LS&S, LLC - Products for the Visually Impaired & Hard of Hearing

**LS &S, LLC. PRIVACY STATEMENT **

This privacy statement covers the site LSSPRODUCTS.COM.  Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users’ privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices. 

  1. What personally identifiable information LS&S, LLC. collects. 
  2. What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site. 
  3. What organization collects the information.
  4. How LS&S, LLC. uses the information.
  5. With whom LS&S, LLC. may share user information. 
  6. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 
  7. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under LS&S,  LLC. control. 
  8. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.   

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact info@lssproducts.com by email.  

#### Information Collection 

LS&S, LLC. is the sole owner of the information collected on LSSPRODUCTS.COM. LS&S, LLC. collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site. 

## Order 

We request information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date).   This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer’s orders.   If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user. 

### Profile 

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users.   A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences.   Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them.   We do not share your profile with other third parties.   Your profile is shared together with your personally identifiable information. 

### Cookies 

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user.   Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site.   We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies.   For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates.   A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. 

### Log Files 

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files.   This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.   IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.  

**Communications from the Site**

## Special Offers and Updates 

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

## Newsletter 

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address.   Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications.   Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

## Service Announcements 

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement.   For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email.   Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account.   However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

Customer Service 

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes. 

**Sharing**

## Legal Disclaimer 

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site. 

## Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable) 

We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers.   This is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

**These are the instances in which we will share users’ personal information:**

We DO NOT Share Personal Information with Third Parties. 

Third Party Intermediaries 

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

Business Transitions 

In the event LS&S, LLC. goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.   Users will be notified via email prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users’ personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section. 

Choice/Opt-out 

Our users are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information.   For example, our order form has an ‘opt-out’ mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don’t want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists.  

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at info@lssproducts.com. 

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties.   We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party. 

## Links 

This Web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we, LS&S, LLC. , are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.   We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.   This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

Surveys 

From time-to-time, our site requests information from users via surveys or contests.   Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information.   The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).   Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes.   Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site.   Users’ personally identifiable information is not shared with third parties unless we give prior notice and choice. Though we may use an intermediary to conduct these surveys or contests, they may not use users’ personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

Security 

This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information.   When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL.   While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’.       

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line.   All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices.   Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information.   Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices.   Every year, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users’ information is protected.   Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment. 

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to info@lssproducts.com. 

## Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information 

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the [member information page] or by emailing our Customer Support at info@lssproducts.com **.**   Or, contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. 

##  

## Notification of Changes 

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.   We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.  

If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.   However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner.   In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.  

## Contact Information 

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 

Phone 847-498-9777 

Fax 847-498-1482 

Email [info@lssproducts.com](mailto:info@lssproducts.com)

Postal Address PO Box 673   Northbrook, IL   60065
